# **Gabrielle Jacobs**

## Web Producer

McKinney, TX, 75072

469-626-7843

in Linkedin.com/in/gabrielle-jacobs

GMJacobsDev.com

Github.com/GabbyJ



#### **PROFILE**

Web producer with 7+ years experience in several industries with a background in content management, web development and multimedia. Looking to obtain a position in a professional, dynamic environment where I can further develop my project management skills and where my experience can contribute to the success of the company.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Web Producer**

*Neighborly* 🗷

- Remote, Irving, TX Project Manager Lead or Assistant for 4 website migrations from Wordpress or
- Coordinate with the Brand, SEO, Product Managers, Developers, Graphics, Legal, and other stakeholders as needed
- Ensure timelines are met, provide quality assurance, and documentation
- Continue Digital Operations Specialist responsibilities

#### **Digital Operations Specialist**

*Neighborly* 🗷

- Lead point of contact and content maintainer for 5 companies and their 1000+ franchise owners using Drupal, Wordpress, and Enterprise CMS Crownpeak
- Decreased ticket turnaround time by 70%

Drupal to Enterprise CMS Crownpeak

- Decreased project budget by thousands and multiple hours by building custom pages using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Coordinate with the Development, SEO, Graphics, Marketing, and Brand teams using Agile and task management boards
- Work as a team with other Specialists to maintain content for 12 other companies and their franchise owners using Wordpress, Strapi, and Crownpeak

#### **Digital Content Manager**

Wieck ☑

- Supervise 3-7 Content Management Specialists and provide qualty assurance for their work
- Decentralize knowledge by providing updates, lessons, documentation, and tutorials for new technologies and processes to employees and other managers
- Build trust, bonds, and support to employees by providing monthly 1-on-1 trainings, recaps, and reviews
- Continue Digital Content and Wordpress Lead responsibilities

10/2023 - Present

06/2021 - Present Remote, Irving, TX

12/2020 - 05/2021 Richardson, TX

#### **Digital Content and Wordpress Lead**

Wieck 🗷

11/2019 – 12/2020 Richardson, TX

- Fix bugs and add website features to production 80% quicker than average by streamlining the ticketing process
- Improve the design and function of custom pages by adding CSS/ JS customizations
- Achieve a 1-on-1 line of communication for all 6 Wordpress clients to provide assistance, updates, and maintenance 50% faster
- Create custom templates from stage to production 60% quicker by both streamlining the ticketing process and providing unique customization knowledge
- Continue Content Management Specialist duties

#### **Digital Content Management Specialist**

Wieck 🛮

06/2017 – 11/2019 Richardson, TX

- 1 of 4 employees responsible for updating 15+ websites with releases, social media, images, videos, and graphics
- Provide internal and external support with an average 30 min turnaround for multiple major car, health, and news corporations, an airline, and others
- Inform thousands of people on important corporate news within 30 mins through custom email blasts for 10+ countries/divisions

#### **SKILLS**

**Web Tools** — Wordpress, Drupal, Headless CMS (Contentful), Enterprise CMS (Crownpeak), Netlify, Git •

**Languages** — *HTML*, *CSS*, *Javascript* (*ES6*) • **Frameworks/Libraries** — *SCSS* (*Sass*), *Bootstrap*, *jQuery*, *React*, *Node* • **Dev Tools** — *Visual Studio Code*, *Git*, *Github*, *NPM* •

**Design Tools** — Photoshop, Adobe XD, Canva • **Miscellaneous** — Responsive Design, WCAG Accessibility, SEO, Jira, Google Analytics, Agile, Microsoft Office • **Soft Skills** — Problem Solving, Creativity, Willingness to learn, Self Starter, Dependable, Communication, Teamwork

#### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Graphic Communications & Multimedia

California University of Pennsylvania

08/2012 – 12/2015 California, PA

#### **CERTIFICATES**

#### **Responsive Web Design**

FreeCodeCamp - Proven knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, Responsiveness, and Accessibility - Completed: 2019

#### **HubSpot SEO**

Proven knowldge of techincal SEO, keyword research, link building, and optimization - Completed: March 2022

#### **COMMUNITY CONTRIBUTIONS**

#### One Community Church

Digital/Web Team Volunteer

01/2023 - Present

Plano, TX

- Update and maintain the One Community Church website, app and YouTube channel
- Coordinate with the Photography, Writing, Graphics and Video teams to achieve an in-sync, modern, effortless appearance of digital assets
- Created scheduling to ensure full coverage of weekend maintenance tasks
- Leading the accessibility initiative of the website's ongoing redesign